urrently advancing through preclinical development. Immunology In February 2017 we submitted an investigational new drug application (IND) for a new biologic that we are developing, NKTR-358, which is designed to correct the underlying immune system imbalance in the body that occurs in patients with autoimmune disease. The breakdown of mechanisms assuring recognition of self and non-self is what underlies all autoimmune diseases. A failure of the body's self-tolerance mechanisms is known to result from pathogenic auto reactive T lymphocytes. By increasing the number of regulatory T cells (which are specific immune cells in the body that modulate the immune system and prevent autoimmune disease by maintaining self-tolerance), these pathogenic auto reactive T cells can be reduced and the proper balance of effector and regulatory T cells can be achieved to restore the body's self-tolerance mechanisms. There is consistent evidence that suboptimal regulatory T cell numbers and their lack of activity play a significant role in a myriad of autoimmune diseases. NKTR-358 is designed to optimally target the IL-2 receptor complex in order to stimulate proliferation and growth of regulatory T cells. NKTR-358 is being developed as a once or twice monthly self-administered injection for a number of autoimmune diseases. On July 23, 2017, we entered into a worldwide license agreement with Eli Lilly and Company (Lilly) to co-develop NKTR-358. We received an initial payment of $150.0 million in September 2017 and are eligible for up to an additional $250.0 million for development and regulatory milestones. We will be responsible for completing Phase 1 clinical development and certain drug product development and supply activities. We will also share Phase 2 development costs with Lilly, with 75% of those costs borne by Lilly and 25% of the costs borne by us. We will have the option to contribute funding to Phase 3 development on an indication-by-indication basis, ranging from zero to 25% of the global Phase 3 development costs. We are eligible for tiered royalties on global sales up to the low twenties that escalate based upon our level of our contribution to Phase 3 development costs and the level of global product annual sales. Lilly will be responsible for all costs of global commercialization and we will have an option to co-promote in the U.S. under certain conditions. In March 2017, we began the first Phase 1 dose-finding trial of NKTR-358 to evaluate single-ascending doses of NKTR-358 in approximately 50 healthy patients. The study is still ongoing. The Phase 1 multiple-ascending dose 5 trial to evaluate NKTR-358 in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is expected to be initiated in the second quarter of 2018. Pain - NKTR-181 NKTR-181 is a novel mu-opioid analgesic drug candidate for chronic pain conditions. NKTR-181 is currently in Phase 3 clinical development, which we call the SUMMIT Phase 3 program, which includes the SUMMIT-07 efficacy study, a human abuse potential (HAP) study, and the SUMMIT-LTS long-term safety study. On March 20, 2017, we announced that NKTR-181 met its primary and secondary endpoints in the SUMMIT-07 Phase 3 efficacy study. We enrolled the first patient in the first SUMMIT-07 study in February 2015, and we completed enrollment in the study in late 2016. The SUMMIT-07 study compared twice-daily dosing of NKTR-181 tablets to placebo in the treatment of over 600 patients with moderate to severe chronic low back pain who were new to opioid therapy (opioid-na ve). SUMMIT-07 evaluated four analgesic doses of NKTR-181 (100 mg, 200 mg, 300 mg and 400 mg). Patients in the trial achieved an average pain score reduction of over 65% (from 6.73 at screening to 2.32 at randomization) during the dose titration period. The primary efficacy endpoint of the study demonstrated significantly improved chronic back pain relief with NKTR-181 compared to placebo (p=0.0019). Key secondary endpoints of the study also achieved high statistical significance. The study demonstrated that NKTR-181 had a favorable safety profile and was well tolerated. On July 18, 2017, we announced positive top-line data for our pivotal human abuse potential study (HAP) for NKTR-181. The HAP study was designed to confirm and assess the relative oral abuse potential of NKTR-181, at its maximum analgesic therapeutic, dose (400 mg) studied in the SUMMIT-07 trial and at a supratherapeutic dose (3 times to 12 times greater than the analgesic dose range of 100 mg to 400 mg used in the SUMMIT-07 trial), compared to common therapeutic doses of oxycodone (40 mg and 60 mg) in 54 healthy non-dependent recreational drug users. For the primary endpoint of Drug Liking, NKTR-181 (400 mg and 600 mg) rated less likable compared to oxycodone 40 mg and 60 mg (p<0.0001), and a supratherapeutic dose of NKTR-181 (1200 mg) rated less likable than oxycodone 60 mg (p=0.0071). Key secondary endpoints of Area Under Effect for Drug Liking (0-1 hours, 0-2 hours, 0-3 hours), Drug High and Take Drug Again scores met statistical significance for all doses of NKTR-181 (1200 mg, 600 mg, 400 mg) compared to oxycodone (60 mg). The SUMMIT Phase 3 program also includes a 52-week long-term safety study, which we call SUMMIT-LTS. SUMMIT-LTS is evaluating the long-term safety and tolerability of NKTR-181 in 638 patients (opioid-na ve and opioid-experienced) with moderate to severe chronic low pain or chronic non-cancer pain. The study was completed in December 2017. Following our success of the SUMMIT-07 Phase 3 efficacy study and the HAP study, we are seeking a partner to support future development and commercialization activities for NKTR-181. We have completed pre-NDA meetings with FDA and we are currently planning to file an NDA for NKTR-181 in the first half of 2018. Oncology - ONZEALD TM ONZEALD TM (also known as NKTR-102, etirinotecan pegol) is our next-generation topoisomerase I inhibitor proprietary drug candidate. On March 17, 2015, we announced top-line data from a Phase 3 clinical study for ONZEALD TM , which we call the BEACON study (BrEAst Cancer Outcomes with NKTR-102), as a single-agent therapy for women with advanced metastatic breast cancer. The BEACON study compared ONZEALD TM to an active control arm comprised of a single chemotherapy agent of physician s choice (TPC) in patients who were heavily pre-treated with a median of three prior therapies for metastatic disease. In a top-line analysis of 852 patients from the trial, ONZEALD TM provided a 2.1 month improvement in median overall survival over TPC (12.4 months for patients receiving ONZEALD TM compared to 10.3 months for patients receiving TPC). Based on a stratified log-rank analysis, the primary endpoint measuring the Hazard Ratio (HR) for survival in the ONZEALD TM group compared to the active control arm was 0.87 with a p-value of 0.08, which did not achieve statistical significance. Secondary endpoints in the BEACON study included objective response rate and progression-free survival, which did not achieve statistical significance in the study. We also announced that we observed a significant overall survival benefit in two pre-specified subgroup populations patients with a history of brain metastases and patients with baseline liver metastases at study entry. We have explored future regulatory and development paths forward for ONZEALD TM with the European Union (EU) and U.S. health authorities. In Europe, we met with the National Authorities in Sweden and the United Kingdom, as well as the European Medicines Agency (EMA) to discuss the BEACON data. In June 2016, we filed a Marketing Authorization Application (MAA) for conditional approval of ONZEALD TM for adult patients with advanced breast cancer who have brain metastases and began enrolling in the ATTAIN study, which compares the overall survival in patients with breast cancer and brain metastases treated with ONZEALD TM versus physicians treatment of choice. On July 21, 201
